<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="SkyModelUtils" inherits="Node3D" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
				<brief_description>
								Utility class providing helper methods for configuring the sky model and scene lighting.
				</brief_description>
				<description>
								[SkyModelUtils] is a Godot native extension utility class that exposes helper methods used when preparing sky model parameters from GDScript.
								The class does not store any sky model state and does not generate textures directly. Instead, it provides static helper methods for generating altitude sample arrays and for estimating a suitable sunlight color temperature for Godot's light settings.
								The altitude generation methods are useful when creating multiple sky textures for different observer heights. [method generate_linear_altitudes] creates evenly spaced altitude values, while [method generate_non_linear_altitudes] creates values distributed non-linearly between the minimum and maximum altitude.
								[method compute_sun_light_temperature] provides an artistic approximation of direct sunlight color temperature. It is intended for use with Godot's light temperature settings and should not be treated as a physically exact atmospheric simulation result.
				</description>
				<tutorials>
				</tutorials>
				<methods>
								<method name="compute_sun_light_temperature" qualifiers="static">
												<return type="float" />
												<param index="0" name="elevation" type="float" />
												<param index="1" name="altitude" type="float" />
												<param index="2" name="visibility" type="float" />
												<description>
																Estimates the color temperature of direct sunlight from the given atmospheric parameters.
																[param elevation] is the solar elevation angle in degrees. Low or negative elevations return a warm color temperature near the horizon, while higher elevations approach a neutral daylight value.
																[param altitude] is the observer altitude above the ground, in meters. Higher altitude slightly increases the returned temperature because less atmosphere is assumed to affect the direct sunlight.
																[param visibility] is the horizontal visibility, or meteorological range, in kilometers. Lower visibility represents a hazier atmosphere and slightly lowers the returned temperature, producing warmer sunlight.
																The returned value is an approximate correlated color temperature in kelvin. It is intended mainly for Godot's [code]light_temperature[/code] property and should be used as an artistic helper rather than as a physically exact result.
												</description>
								</method>
								<method name="generate_linear_altitudes" qualifiers="static">
												<return type="PackedFloat32Array" />
												<param index="0" name="min_altitude" type="float" />
												<param index="1" name="max_altitude" type="float" />
												<param index="2" name="count" type="int" />
												<description>
																Generates evenly spaced altitude values between [param min_altitude] and [param max_altitude].
																[param min_altitude] is the first altitude value in the generated array, in meters.
																[param max_altitude] is the last altitude value in the generated array, in meters.
																[param count] is the number of altitude values to generate.
																Returns a [PackedFloat32Array] containing [param count] values. If [param count] is less than or equal to [code]0[/code], an empty array is returned. If [param count] is [code]1[/code], the returned array contains only [param min_altitude].
																This method is useful when sky textures should be generated at uniformly distributed observer altitudes.
												</description>
								</method>
								<method name="generate_non_linear_altitudes" qualifiers="static">
												<return type="PackedFloat32Array" />
												<param index="0" name="min_altitude" type="float" />
												<param index="1" name="max_altitude" type="float" />
												<param index="2" name="count" type="int" />
												<param index="3" name="exponent" type="float" />
												<description>
																Generates non-linearly spaced altitude values between [param min_altitude] and [param max_altitude].
																[param min_altitude] is the first altitude value in the generated array, in meters.
																[param max_altitude] is the last altitude value in the generated array, in meters.
																[param count] is the number of altitude values to generate.
																[param exponent] controls the distribution of the generated samples. Values greater than [code]1.0[/code] place more samples near [param min_altitude]. A value of [code]1.0[/code] produces the same distribution as linear spacing. If the exponent is less than or equal to [code]0.0[/code], it is treated as [code]1.0[/code].
																Returns a [PackedFloat32Array] containing [param count] values. If [param count] is less than or equal to [code]0[/code], an empty array is returned. If [param count] is [code]1[/code], the returned array contains only [param min_altitude].
																This method is useful when more texture samples are needed near the ground, where changes in atmospheric appearance are usually more noticeable.
												</description>
								</method>
				</methods>
</class>
